<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stroom – job</title>
    <link>/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/tags/job/</link>
    <description>Recent content in job on Stroom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/tags/job/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Stroom Jobs</title>
      <link>/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/docs/user-guide/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/docs/user-guide/jobs/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;There are various jobs that run in the background within Stroom.
Among these are jobs that control pipeline processing, removing old files from the file system, checking the status of nodes and volumes etc.
Each task executes at a different time depending on the purpose of the task. There are three ways that a task can be executed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scheduled jobs execute periodically according to a cron schedule.
These include jobs such as cleaning the file system where Stroom only needs to perform this action once a day and can do so overnight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequency controlled jobs are executed every X seconds, minutes, hours etc.
Most of the jobs that execute with a given frequency are status checking jobs that perform a short lived action fairly frequently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributed jobs are only applicable to stream processing with a pipeline.
Distributed jobs are executed by a worker node as soon as a worker has available threads to execute a jobs and the task distributor has work available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A list of task types and their execution method can be seen by opening &lt;em&gt;Monitoring/Jobs&lt;/em&gt; from the main menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TODO&lt;/strong&gt;: image&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expanding each task type allows you to configure how a task behaves on each node:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TODO&lt;/strong&gt;: image&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;account-maintenance&#34;&gt;Account Maintenance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This job checks user accounts on the system and de-activates them under the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An unused account that has been inactive for longer than the age configured by &lt;code&gt;stroom.security.identity.passwordPolicy.neverUsedAccountDeactivationThreshold&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An account that has been inactive for longer than the age configured by &lt;code&gt;stroom.security.identity.passwordPolicy.unusedAccountDeactivationThreshold&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attribute-value-data-retention&#34;&gt;Attribute Value Data Retention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deletes Meta attribute values (additional and less valuable metadata) older than &lt;code&gt;stroom.data.meta.metaValue.deleteAge&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-delete&#34;&gt;Data Delete&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before data is physically removed from the database and file system it is marked as logically deleted by adding a flag to the metadata record in the database.
Data can be logically deleted by a user from the UI or via a process such as data retention.
Data is deleted logically as it is faster to do than a physical delete (important in the UI), and it also allows for data to be restored (undeleted) from the UI.
This job performs the actual physical deletion of data that has been marked logically deleted for longer than the duration configured with &lt;code&gt;stroom.data.store.deletePurgeAge&lt;/code&gt;.
All data files associated with a metadata record are deleted from the file system before the metadata is physically removed from the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-processor&#34;&gt;Data Processor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processes data by finding data that matches processing filters on each pipeline.
When enabled, each worker node asks the master node for data processing tasks.
The master node creates tasks based on processing filters added to the &lt;code&gt;Processors&lt;/code&gt; screen of each pipeline and supplies them to the requesting workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feed-based-data-retention&#34;&gt;Feed Based Data Retention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This job uses the retention property of each feed to logically delete data from the associated feed that is older than the retention period.
The recommended way of specifying data retention rules is via the data retention policy feature, but feed based retention still exists for backwards compatibility.
Feed based data retention will be removed in a future release and should be considered deprecated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;file-system-clean-deprecated&#34;&gt;File System Clean (deprecated)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the previous incarnation of the &lt;code&gt;Data Delete&lt;/code&gt; job.
This job scans the file system looking for files that are no longer associated with metadata in the database or where the metadata is marked as deleted and deletes the files if this is the case.
The process is slow to run as it has to traverse all stored data files and examine each.
However, this version of the data deletion process was created when metadata was deleted immediately, i.e. not marked for future physical deletion, so was the only way to perform this clean up activity at the time.
This job will be removed in a future release. The &lt;code&gt;Data Delete&lt;/code&gt; job should be used instead from now on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;file-system-volume-status&#34;&gt;File System Volume Status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scans your data volumes to ensure they are available and determines how much free space they have.
Records this status in the Volume Status table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;index-searcher-cache-refresh&#34;&gt;Index Searcher Cache Refresh&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refresh references to Lucene index searchers that have been cached for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;index-shard-delete&#34;&gt;Index Shard Delete&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently index shards that have been logically deleted are physically deleted from the file system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;index-shard-retention&#34;&gt;Index Shard Retention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently index shards that are older then their retention period are logically deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;index-volume-status&#34;&gt;Index Volume Status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scans your index volumes to ensure they are available and determines how much free space they have.
Records this status in the Index Volume Status table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;index-writer-cache-sweep&#34;&gt;Index Writer Cache Sweep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently entries in the Index Shard Writer cache are evicted based on the time-to-live, time-to-idle and cache size settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;index-writer-flush&#34;&gt;Index Writer Flush&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently in-memory changes to the index shards are flushed to the file system and committed to the index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-heap-histogram-statistics&#34;&gt;Java Heap Histogram Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently heap histogram statistics will be captured.
This can be useful for diagnosing issues or seeing where memory is being used.
Each run will result in a JVM pause so car should be taken when running this on a production system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;node-status&#34;&gt;Node Status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently we try write stats about node status including JVM and memory usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pipeline-destination-roll&#34;&gt;Pipeline Destination Roll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently rolling pipeline destinations, e.g. a Rolling File Appender are checked to see if they need to be rolled.
This frequency should be at least as short as the most frequent rolling frequency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;policy-based-data-retention&#34;&gt;Policy Based Data Retention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the policy based data retention rules over the data and logically delete and data that should no longer be retained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;processor-task-queue-statistics&#34;&gt;Processor Task Queue Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently statistics about the state of the stream processing task queue are captured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;processor-task-retention&#34;&gt;Processor Task Retention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently failed and completed tasks are checked to see if they are older than the delete age threshold set by &lt;code&gt;stroom.processor.deleteAge&lt;/code&gt;.
Any that are older than this threshold are deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;property-cache-reload&#34;&gt;Property Cache Reload&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stroom&amp;rsquo;s configuration properties can each be configured globally in the database.
This job controls the frequency that each node refreshes the values of its properties cache from the global database values.
See also &lt;a href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/docs/user-guide/properties/&#34;&gt;Properties&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proxy-aggregation&#34;&gt;Proxy Aggregation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you front Stroom with an Stroom proxy which is configured to &amp;lsquo;store&amp;rsquo; rather than &amp;lsquo;store/forward&amp;rsquo;, then this task when run will pick up all files in the proxy repository dir, aggregate them by feed and bring them into Stroom.
It uses the system property &lt;code&gt;stroom.proxyDir&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;query-history-clean&#34;&gt;Query History Clean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently items in the query history are removed from the history if their age is older than &lt;code&gt;stroom.history.daysRetention&lt;/code&gt; or if the number of items in the history exceeds &lt;code&gt;stroom.history.itemsRetention&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ref-data-off-heap-store-purge&#34;&gt;Ref Data Off-heap Store Purge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purges all data older than the purge age defined by property &lt;code&gt;stroom.pipeline.purgeAge&lt;/code&gt;.
See also &lt;a href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/docs/user-guide/pipelines/reference-data/#purging-old-reference-data&#34;&gt;Reference Data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solr-index-optimise&#34;&gt;Solr Index Optimise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently Solr index segments are explicitly optimised by merging them into one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solr-index-retention&#34;&gt;Solr Index Retention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How frequently a process is run to delete items from the Solr indexes that don&amp;rsquo;t meet the retention rule of that index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sql-stats-database-aggregation&#34;&gt;SQL Stats Database Aggregation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This job controls the frequency that the database statistics aggregation process is run.
This process takes the entries in &lt;code&gt;SQL_STAT_VAL_SRC&lt;/code&gt; and merges them into the main statistics tables &lt;code&gt;SQL_STAT_KEY&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;SQL_STAT_KEY&lt;/code&gt;.
As this process is reliant on data flushed by the &lt;em&gt;SQL Stats In Memory Flush&lt;/em&gt; job it is advisable to schedule it to run after that, leaving some time for the in-memory flush to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sql-stats-in-memory-flush&#34;&gt;SQL Stats In Memory Flush&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQL Statistics are initially held and aggregated in memory.
This job controls the frequency that the in memory statistics are flushed from the in memory buffer to the staging table &lt;code&gt;SQL_STAT_VAL_SRC&lt;/code&gt; in the database.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Task Management</title>
      <link>/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/docs/howtos/general/taskshowto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/docs/howtos/general/taskshowto/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Various
&lt;a href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/docs/user-guide/jobs/&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/a&gt;
run in the background within Stroom. This HOWTO demonstrates how to manage these tasks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;assumptions&#34;&gt;Assumptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Sections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an account with the &lt;code&gt;Administrator&lt;/code&gt; Application &lt;a href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/docs/user-guide/roles/&#34;&gt;Permission&lt;/a&gt; is currently logged in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proxy Aggregation Tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we have a multi node Stroom cluster with two nodes, &lt;code&gt;stroomp00&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;stroomp01&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stream Processor Tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we have a multi node Stroom cluster with two nodes, &lt;code&gt;stroomp00&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;stroomp01&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when demonstrating adding a new node to an existing cluster, the new node is &lt;code&gt;stroomp02&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proxy-aggregation&#34;&gt;Proxy Aggregation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;turn-off-proxy-aggregation&#34;&gt;Turn Off Proxy Aggregation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We first select the &lt;code&gt;Monitoring&lt;/code&gt; item of the &lt;strong&gt;Main Menu&lt;/strong&gt; to bring up the &lt;code&gt;Monitoring&lt;/code&gt; sub-menu.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Monitoring sub-menu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then move down and select the &lt;code&gt;Jobs&lt;/code&gt; sub-item to be presented with the &lt;code&gt;Jobs&lt;/code&gt; configuration tab as seen below.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-JobsTab-00.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-JobsTab-00.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-JobsTab-00.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-JobsTab-00.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Jobs Management - management tab&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this we can select the &lt;code&gt;Proxy Aggregation&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;Job&lt;/em&gt; whose check-box is selected and the tab will show the individual Stroom Processor nodes
in the deployment.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-00.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-00.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-00.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-00.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Jobs Management - Proxy Aggregation Job&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this, uncheck the &lt;code&gt;Enabled&lt;/code&gt; check-boxes for both nodes and also the main Proxy Aggregation check-box to see.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-01.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-01.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-01.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Jobs Management - Proxy Aggregation Job Off&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, no new proxy aggregation will occur and any inbound files received by the Store Proxies will accumulate in the proxy storage area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;turn-on-proxy-aggregation&#34;&gt;Turn On Proxy Aggregation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We first select the &lt;code&gt;Monitoring&lt;/code&gt; item of the &lt;strong&gt;Main Menu&lt;/strong&gt; to bring up the &lt;code&gt;Monitoring&lt;/code&gt; sub-menu.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Monitoring sub-menu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then move down and select the &lt;code&gt;Jobs&lt;/code&gt; sub-item then select the &lt;code&gt;Proxy Aggregation&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;Job&lt;/em&gt; to be presented with the &lt;code&gt;Jobs&lt;/code&gt; configuration tab as seen below.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-01.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-01.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-ProxyAggregation-01.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Jobs Management - Proxy Aggregation Job Off&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, re-enable each node&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;Proxy Aggregation&lt;/code&gt; check-box and the main &lt;code&gt;Proxy Aggregation&lt;/code&gt; check-box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking the check-boxes, perform a refresh of the display by pressing
the &lt;em&gt;Refresh&lt;/em&gt; icon 






  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/icons/refresh.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/icons/refresh.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/icons/refresh.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/icons/refresh.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI RefreshButton&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;on the top right of the lower (node display) pane. You should note the &lt;code&gt;Last Executed&lt;/code&gt; date/time change to see&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;






  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-TestProxyAggregation-00.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-TestProxyAggregation-00.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-TestProxyAggregation-00.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-TestProxyAggregation-00.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Test Feed - Re-enable Proxy Aggregation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stream-processors&#34;&gt;Stream Processors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enable-stream-processors&#34;&gt;Enable Stream Processors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable the &lt;code&gt;Stream Processors&lt;/code&gt; task, move to the &lt;code&gt;Monitoring&lt;/code&gt; item of the &lt;strong&gt;Main Menu&lt;/strong&gt; and select it to bring up the &lt;code&gt;Monitoring&lt;/code&gt; sub-menu.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Monitoring sub-menu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then move down and select the &lt;code&gt;Jobs&lt;/code&gt; sub-item to be presented with the &lt;code&gt;Jobs&lt;/code&gt; configuration tab as seen below.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-00.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-00.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-00.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-00.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Jobs Management - management tab&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this, we select the &lt;code&gt;Stream Processor&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;Job&lt;/em&gt; whose check-box is not selected and the tab will show the individual Stroom Processor
nodes in the Stroom deployment.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-01.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-01.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-01.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Jobs Management - Stream Processor&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, if it was a single node Stroom deployment, you would only see the one node at the bottom of the &lt;code&gt;Jobs&lt;/code&gt; configuration tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We enable nodes nodes by selecting their check-boxes as well as the main &lt;code&gt;Stream Processors&lt;/code&gt; check-box. Do so.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-02.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-02.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-02.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-02.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Jobs Management - Stream Processor enabled&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is it. Stroom will automatically take note of these changes and internally start each node&amp;rsquo;s Stroom Processor task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enable-stream-processors-on-new-node&#34;&gt;Enable Stream Processors On New Node&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When one expands a Multi Node Stroom cluster deployment, after the installation of the Stroom Proxy and Application software and
services on the new node, we need to enable it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;Stream Processors&lt;/code&gt; task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable the &lt;code&gt;Stream Processors&lt;/code&gt; for this new node, move to the &lt;code&gt;Monitoring&lt;/code&gt; item of the &lt;strong&gt;Main Menu&lt;/strong&gt; and select it to bring up the &lt;code&gt;Monitoring&lt;/code&gt; sub-menu.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-MonitoringSubmenu-00.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Monitoring sub-menu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then move down and select the &lt;code&gt;Jobs&lt;/code&gt; sub-item to be presented with the &lt;code&gt;Jobs&lt;/code&gt; configuration tab as seen below.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-00.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-00.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-00.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NodeProcessors-00.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Jobs Management - management tab&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this we select the &lt;code&gt;Stream Processor&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;Job&lt;/em&gt; whose check-box is selected&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NewNodeProcessors-00.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NewNodeProcessors-00.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NewNodeProcessors-00.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NewNodeProcessors-00.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Jobs Management - Stream Processor new node&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enable the new node by selecting it&amp;rsquo;s check-box.&lt;/p&gt;







  
  
  
  
  







  



&lt;div class=&#34;card rounded shadow-stroom p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;width: fit-content;&#34;&gt;

  &lt;a title=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NewNodeProcessors-01.png&#34; href=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NewNodeProcessors-01.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&#34;margin-block-end: 0px&#34; &gt;
      
      &lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/stroom-docs/hugo-docsy/images/HOWTOs/UI-NewNodeProcessors-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;images/HOWTOs/UI-NewNodeProcessors-01.png&#34;&gt;
      

      
      &lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
        &lt;hr style=&#34;border-top: 1px solid #ddd; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:4px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption class=&#34;card-text&#34; style=&#34;font-size: smaller; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Stroom UI Jobs Management - Stream Processor enabled on new node&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
